"Hokuto City Municipal Bus Stop"
"Slow"
"School Zone"
"Owner's Manual"
あっ
あった
"Helmet holder"
Here it is.
これか
This must be it.
あれ…
Huh...?
ヤバっ！
Uh-oh.
"2nd Year"
私！バイクで学校に来たの！
I rode my motorbike to school today!
え～っ！
--Huh?!
おい　マジかよ！
Hey, are you serious?
すご～い　いつ免許取ったの？
Amazing! When did you get your license?
何乗ってんだよ？
What do you ride?
見せて　見せて～
Show me! Show me!
--What kind of bike is it?
--That's awesome!
すっげ～！
えっと…
Oh, um...
すごいな～
初めての小さな旅路
目的地なら　いらないよ
何もない私の頬に
手招きするように風が吹く
寄り道　回り道
いつもの景色も鮮やかに
右手を捻る度　何度でも胸が弾むから
さあ　ギアを上げて　顔を上げて
どこまでも伸びてく道だって
昨日より少し遠くまで
君となら怖くない　どこだって
私一人では　作れない風だ
またパスタ？
Pasta again?
だって好きなんだもん
Well, I like it.
ねぇねぇ　一緒に食べない？
Hey, want to eat with me?
ごめんなさい　ちょっと用があるから
I'm sorry, but there's something
I need to take care of.
そっかぁ　じゃあまたね
Okay. Some other time, then.
"Oyakodon"
は～い
Okay. Today, I'd like for all of you...
to make a drawstring bag like this one.
今日はね　皆さんにはこんな巾着を作ってもらおうと思うのよね
巾着…
Drawstring bag...?
布はね…ここにあるのを自由に使っていいですからね
For the fabric, you are free
to use anything in here.
教科書どおりに作ってくださいね
Please follow your textbooks.
え～うまい！なんで？
Wow, how come you're so good?
私にも教えて教えて～
Show me how to do it, too!
どんなやつにしたの？
What kind did you choose?
私はこれ
I got this one.
好きだね～その色
You sure like that color, don't you?
そんなに大きいの何に使うの？
What are you going to use all that for?
Money must be tight.
貧乏性だなぁ
まさか夜逃げの準備とか？
Don't tell me you're getting
ready to run away.
ヘルメットとグローブを入れようと思って　バイクの
I was thinking of putting my helmet
and gloves for my motorbike in it.
えっ　免許取ったの？
Huh? You have your license?
マジ？何乗ってんだよ？
For real? What do you ride?
スーパーカブ　中古の
A Super Cub. A used one.
なんだよ　カブかよ～
Oh, a Cub? That's more of a scooter
than a motorbike, isn't it?
バイクってか原付じゃん　それ
カブってあれでしょ？おソバ屋さんとか　新聞配達とかの
A Cub is that one kind, right?
The one that soba restaurants
and newspapers use for deliveries?
あなたはカブに乗っているの？
You ride a Cub?
中古だけど
Well, a used one.
あとで見せてくれるかしら
Would you mind letting me see it later?
えっ？
Huh?
授業…終わったあとなら
Maybe after our classes are over.
そっ　じゃあ約束ね
Sure. Okay, see you then.
今日の数学全然わかんなかった～
I didn't get today's math at all.
確かに難しかった～
It was hard, all right.
ってか教えんのヘタクソなんだもん
I mean, the way she
teaches it is so bad...
That's true.
それな～
まぁ　しようがないよ
Well, what can we do?
はいこれ　忘れ物よ
Here, you forgot something.
あ…ありがとう
Th-Thanks.
今日も頑張ろう
Let's give our best today.
うん　頑張ろう
Mm-hmm, let's.
これ
This is...
へぇ！キャブ式カブの極上品じゃない
Wow! You have a prime
carburetor-style Cub!
走行は 500 キロちょっと…
It only has a bit over 500 kilos on it.
Oh, and the tires are still brand new!
タイヤもまだまっさらね
Ah, Cubs really are the coolest.
やっぱカブはカッコイイわ
Oh, and you have an Arai Classic helmet.
That's a great match for a Cub.
ヘルメットはアライのクラシックかぁ
カブによく似合ってるわね
私はショウエイのホーネット
I use a Shoei Hornet, myself.
グローブは？何を使ってるの？
What about your gloves?
What are you using?
えっ？
Huh? Oh, let's see...
あ…えっと
グリップスワニーね！
Grip Swany, huh?
Mine are non-slip work gloves.
私は滑り止め軍手
軍手…
Work gloves?
そっ　軍手
Yep, work gloves.
私もバイクで通学してるんだけど
I ride my motorbike to school, too.
えっ
Huh?
見る？
Wanna see?
あっ…と…
Oh, um...
うん…
Mm-hmm.
ちょちょちょっと…ちょっとだけ待ってて！
H-H-Hold on! Hold on a minute, right here!
えっ…
Huh?
これって…
Is that...?
ホンダMD90　郵政カブ
A Honda MD90 Postal Cub.
郵便局の…
Like the post office uses.
そっ
Yep. From before environmental
and noise regulations
環境とか騒音の規制で　パワーを落とされる前の原付よ
made them scale back the power on these.
いじり甲斐のない電子制御になる前のカブ
It's a Cub from before they had electronic
controls worth fiddling with.
鉄よ
Steel.
手に入れてからもいろいろ改造して　かなりのスピードが出るようになってるわ
I've souped it up a little since I got it,
and gotten it so it goes pretty fast.
エンジンパーツもブレーキ周りも　サスもタケガワよ
The engine parts, the brakes,
and the suspension are all Takegawa.
マフラーはワンオフのチタン製
The muffler is a one-off titanium piece.
富田林の社屋を建て替えられるくらい貢いだわ
I had to give them nearly enough to
pay off their office in Tondabayashi.
ハァ　熱くなっちゃった
Whew, it's getting warm.
Sorry for doing all the talking.
私ばっかり喋っちゃって悪かったわね
でも　同じカブ乗りと知り合えてうれしいわ
But I'm glad to meet a fellow Cub rider.
それじゃ
See you.
同じクラスの顔と名前しか知らない女の子
A girl in my class, whose name and
face are the only things I know...
明日も私に話しかけてくるんだろうか？
I wonder if she'll talk to me
again tomorrow, too.
とりあえず　カブという共通の話題ならある
For now, we at least have our Cubs
in common to talk about.
彼女の名前は… たしか…
As I recall... her name is...
"Reiko"
"Super Cub Episode 2"
時刻は 7 時 25 分です
The time is now 7:25.
And now for the weather.
はじめに天気予報です
まず７時現在の各地の気温
The current temperature around
the area is 19.7 degrees in Kofu,
甲府は 19.7 度　河口湖は 17.5 度　東京は 18.4 度でした
17.5 degrees at Lake Kawaguchi,
and 18.4 degrees in Tokyo.
Due to a high-pressure system
over the Japanese archipelago,
today's weather for the
Kanto-Koshinetsu region will be sunny.
よし
Good.
おはよ～
Morning.
おはよう
めっちゃかわいい！
お…おはよう
G-Good morning.
Hmm?
うん
Mm-hmm.
"Gyudon"
礼子さん　お弁当一緒に食べない？
Reiko-san, want to eat lunch together?
ごめんなさい　今日のお昼は友達と食べる予定なの
Sorry, I was planning to have
my lunch today with a friend.
そっか～残念
Oh. Oh, well.
また今度ね
Some other time, then.
じゃ　行こうか
All right, let's go.
えっ…
Huh?
ちょ　えっ…ちょっと!?
H-Hold on...
じゃあ　お昼ごはん食べようか！
Okay, ready to have lunch?
友達と一緒にね！
Together, as friends.
いっただきま～す！
Thank you for this food!
こうやってカブに乗っていると
Sitting on my Cub like this,
たとえ止まっていても
it feels like I can go anywhere
I like, as far away as I like,
自分がどこにでも　どこまでも行けるっていう気分を感じられるのよ
even when I'm standing still.
まだ遠くに行ったこと…ないから
I haven't gone all that far away, so...
どこにでも行けるわよ
You can go anywhere you want to.
I mean, you've got a Cub!
だってカブだもん
早く早く！
Hurry, hurry!
おい　待てよ！
Hey, wait up!
試合応援にいくね
I'll be cheering for you at your game.
おぉ　ありがとう
Oh, thank you.
こうやってカブに乗っていると
Sitting on my Cub like this,
たとえ止まっていても
it feels like I can go anywhere
I like, as far away as I like,
自分がどこにでも　どこまでも行けるっていう気分を感じられるのよ
even when I'm standing still.
まだ遠くに行ったこと…ないから
I haven't gone all that far away, so...
どこにでも行けるわよ
You can go anywhere you want to.
I mean, you've got a Cub!
だってカブだもん
どこにでも行ける…
I can go anywhere I want to...
"Mukawa Supermarket"
安っ
That's cheap.
ありがとうございました～
Thank you very much.
いらっしゃいませ！
Welcome.
"2-yen charge for shopping bags"
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much.
学校帰りに買い物をしたり
Up to now, I haven't gone shopping
on the way home from school,
どこかへ行ったりしたことなんて
今まであまりなかった
or anywhere else that much, either.
いつもは曲がらない角を曲がった　私の目の前に広がったのは…
I turned at an intersection
where I always go straight,
and what I found spread out before me...
知らなかった場所
...were unknown places...
知らなかった道
...unknown streets...
そしてきっと…
...and I'm sure...
まだ知らない風景も
...there are unknown sights to see, too.
そうだ　チェーンキー
"Komeri"
Oh, yeah, my chain lock.
あっちはまた明日
I'll go there tomorrow.
スーパーカブで寄り道
Side trips on my Super Cub...
明日の放課後が　ちょっと楽しみになった
I'm kind of looking forward
to tomorrow after school.
すれ違う風　未来に溶けてく
近づいてくる　優しいエンジンの音
透明だった世界に　車輪で色を付けよう
ともに駆け抜けた道
誰にも描けない私の絵になる
遠くで春が呼ぶ　すぐそこかもしれない
できるだけたくさんの　思い出連れてこう
一緒に過ごす日々　見つけた彩りは決して
色褪せない
いつだってずっと　そばにいるよ
"Super Cub Episode 3"
"Things Received"
第３話　「もらったもの」
"Super Cub Episode 3"
"Things Received"
Episode 3: "Things Received."